Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Attack from Second Baleras complete.
What did you do?
Just an idea... I used the Wave Motion Energy as a weapon.
The Wave Motion Gun?
The Yamato appears to have been destroyed.
Send observation data.
After a long, hard journey, they died right before their goal.
What a beautiful ending.
I wonder what the captain was like.
I'd love to have met him, to give him a word of appreciation.
Princess Yurisha seems unwell.
Take her outside.
Let's go.
Something's on the radar, near the point of impact... The Yamato.
AA guns are badly damaged!
Sensors aren't working right!
The planet's collapsing.
Epidra is no more...
A single attack, capable of destroying a planet...
It's the Wave Motion Gun.
I'm seeing fluctuations in the gravitational gradient.
This waveform is definitely that of the Wave Motion Gun.
We will continue, to the inner system.
Even the Wave Motion Gun has difficulty targeting objects at sub-light speeds.
Without going deep into their range, we have no way to win.
Full speed ahead! Our destination is Garmillas.
The Yamato is approaching at sub-light speeds!
Interesting.
Minister Talan from Second Baleras.
My lord, the attack damaged parts of our systems.
Have repairs completed as soon as possible.
But targeting an object at sub-light speed, with the Desler cannon is difficult.
It will slow down in a moment.
My lord, Her Highness Starsha is on the hotline.
She wishes to speak to you directly.
What are you doing, Lord Desler?
Using Wave Motion Energy as a weapon is sheer madness.
Are you here to complain?
Yes.
Complaints, complaints. Every time you come here, it's to complain.
Then why do you not complain to the Terrons?
What do you mean?
The ship you brought here uses Wave Motion Energy as a weapon, as well.
Impossible...
Come to think of it, you saw that your little sister is doing well, yes?
I ordered her kept safe.
What are you thinking, Abelt?
I'm doing this for you.
Stop it.
Starsha...
Please!
I see. How unfortunate.
Stop this, Abelt.
Ships at ten o'clock. Three carriers!
Deploy the Wave Motion Shields.
No, not yet.
Yes, sir.
Half speed... Launch the Hayabusas!
The front carrier fleet will soon encounter the enemy.
Attack.
Launch the Melancas!
Don't let them near the Yamato! Shoot them down!
Hard to starboard. We're heading straight for Garmillas!
Damage to the forward carrier fleet!
The Yamato is still descending.
Protecting the new capital is our only goal.
But nonetheless, we must make a show of this.
This is the Imperial Capitol City of Baleras.
Make it through here, and you'll be at the palace.
Very well... We will now strike at the enemy's heart, Lord Desler's palace!
We've allowed the enemy onto our own soil?
What is the Imperial Guard doing?
Gimleh... He's useless!
Deploy the Wave Motion Shields!
We're going to ram the palace!
Brace for impact!
Is everyone all right?
Everyone, equip weapons.
Assemble a team and take command, Kodai!
Let's get out of here.
Yeah.
I thought you'd say that.
Impossible...
Is our lord safe?
Find him now!
Initiating Deusura decoupling sequence.
Calm down...
The Deusura?
10... 9... 8...
Out of the way!
7... 6...
5... 4... 3... 2... 1... 0...
It's accelerating...
Something has launched from the palace!
I can feel it.
Yuki is aboard it.
No... You left me behind?
This can't be... This can't be!
My lord, Second Baleras will be under our control shortly.
As planned.
Yes.
We shall now begin the operation.
Zar belk.
Dimensional Mobile City Fortress Second Baleras
Minister Talan, the central control system is being taken over from outside!
Find the origin.
The... The command is coming from the Deusura.
Our leader...
Minister Talan, Industrial Sector 633 is entering decoupling sequence.
Impossible...
Why don't you go?
Why don't you go save Yuki?
I'll command the assault team.
Kodai!
Something on radar!
Magnify!
A massive object in orbit!
Estimated mass, 60,000,000 tons.
Descending from Lagrange point L1.
Estimated impact point is the palace. In other words, here.
It continues to descend.
The decoupling command came from Lord Desler!
From our lord?
It will reach point of impact at 2400 gek.
How foolish...
Everyone, evacuate! Declare an emergency in the capital!
This is an emergency! Evacuate the palace at once!
I repeat... This is an emergency! Evacuate the palace at once!
Staying here is dangerous.
Is this... Is this how a leader behaves, Desler?
Guidance beacon, locked.
Docking complete. Connected to Desler Cannon circuit.
Minister Talan is here.
My lord, please tell me your intention!
Why are you dropping Industrial Sector 633 on Baleras?
This is a rite of passage.
A rite of passage?
Baleras and the Yamato will be annihilated together.
And this noble sacrifice will give rise to the rebirth of Garmillas.
After the operation, Second Baleras will land on Iscandar.
I hereby declare this orbital city fortress to be the new capital of Garmillas.
A new center! A new Baleras!
Splendid.
And this Second Baleras will be a bridge between Iscandar and Garmillas.
Twenty minutes until impact.
Prepare to fire the Wave Motion Gun.
Okita...
Only the Wave Motion Gun could destroy that much mass.
Through actions... Not words.
This is the time for everyone to do their best.
What you must do... What only you can do!
That's why I'm going after Yuki—
No!
That is what I must do.
Captain, give me permission to launch in a Zero.
Kodai, you are relieved of your duties as Tactical Officer.
You have another mission... To rescue Operations Officer Mori.
Yes, sir!
I will allow you to take one person.
Thank you!
I, Susumu Kodai, will now go to rescue Operations Officer Mori.
I've got this. In exchange...
Bring her back.
Melda...
I'm simply protecting Lady Yurisha.
Leave this to me.
To us.
Everyone...
You should do what only you can do.
Kodai...
Yeah... Yeah!
Take care of the princess!
I'm serious.
After linking with the core ship,
Company 6 is to load the Deusura ll.
Get that resupply ready!
This is the control room.
Aren't we escaping?
The enemy was using the Wave Motion Gun.
At this rate, the Yamato won't make it to Iscandar.
What are you going to do?
Destroy this.
Seal all emergency vents.
Releasing safety lock. Target is in range.
Adjusting angle of inclination. Raising the bow slightly.
Fix the hull!
Full evacuation! Full evacuation!
Pressure in chamber rising. Energy charge at 120%.
Prepare shock and flash defenses.
4, 3, 2, 1...
Fire!
The Yamato saved us?
The Yamato?
Captain!
633 engaged in orbit. Physical signal lost.
Okay, understood.
My lord, the Desler Cannon is back on line.
It's entering its firing sequence?
Don't worry.
It's over.
This will force the Wave Motion Core out of control.
Yuki...
Thank you for everything. You needn't stay with me anymore.
You should—
Why are you doing all this?
Because I've finally found it.
I finally understand.
What only I can do.
What I must do.
It's...
To protect you!
Fly, Zero!
Even faster! Even higher!
Begin routing surplus energy to the Desler Cannon.
No...
Why, Norran?
Isn't it pretty obvious?
This is my chance to be a real Garmillan.
If my lord learns that I protected this secret weapon,
he may even make me a full Garmillan!
Don't be stupid!
It isn't stupid!
And so... This is goodbye.
Wait!
Norran!
Be well.
Farewell.
Firing hammer system activated.
Focus the energy so that it only strikes the Yamato.
My lord, stop! You're about to fire on your own people!
Desler Cannon firing sequence is about to begin.
That's why I must do it myself.
I must be the one to commit the sin,
of sacrificing the noble Garmillan lives for the future of Great Garmillas.
I shall live with that sin forever.
What?
Warning... Warning... Wave Motion Core has lost control.
Wave Motion Energy has exceeded safety limits. Explosive compression imminent.
Thinking about it...
I never did hear her real name...
Jump!
Y-Yes, sir.
Norran... You're a terrible liar...
All ships behind us have been destroyed! Explosion is incoming!
Evasive maneuvers!
So... Is this how it all ends?
Enemy fortress is collapsing.
What happened?
In the end, I...
I'm not dreaming, am I?
No, this isn't a dream.
Episode 23
One Man's War
This star is the only one
If you look for something so beautiful
It is not something you can see
You will find it inside anyone
Love is the answer
Sorrow and strife
May cloud the blue sky
The overlapping warmth
Becomes a light to illuminate the world
A wish to the infinite universe
All is forgiven
And we all laugh together
Not a trick of the eye
But a dream from the bottom of my heart
No matter what tomorrow brings
Walk on
If you have nothing special
Only the strength to yearn for it
Bound to the limits of time
Create the trace of a miracle
A wish to the infinite universe
All is forgiven
And we all laugh together
Not a trick of the eye
A dream from the bottom of my heart
No matter what tomorrow brings
Walk on
Together with you
Forever
Before them lies a blue planet...
A planet that will bring hope to their own home.
But no people are to be found there, save for a lonely queen.
And her words come as a surprise. She says...
Next time: The Distant Promised Land.
There are 199 days left before humanity is extinct.